Finding Aid for Martha Wright Griffiths Papers 1956-1976
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Sound recordings
  - Phonograph Records
    - "First Ladies of Congress" A public service program of the Office of Women's Activities, Democratic National Committee, 1 phonograph records 33 1/3 rpm (Box 2)
    - "The Leading Question" CBS Radio Network. Discussion with Rep. Curtis on the subject of medical care for the aged March 1962, 1 phonograph records (Box 2)
- Visual Materials
  - Photographs
    - Portraits (Box 59)
  - Films
    The films are part of a "Report from Washington" series, in which Griffiths reported to her constituents on issues before Congress or matters of special concern to her district. The films are all 16 mm., black & white with sound, ca. 5 minutes in duration. The films are listed in chronological order and have numbered for identification, missing numbers were duplicates that have been removed from the collection.) The films were digitized in 2008 and DVD use copies and streaming files wee created. Some streaming files are currently online, others can be mounted online by request to the library reference staff.
    - With Peter T. Jones, deputy assistant secretary for trade policy, Dept. of Commerce April 1, 1962, 851378-1
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 5:00
        [Restricted]
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File: 851378-1, flash-flv
    - Money and credit; Backdoor spending and foreign aid August 27, 1961, 851378-2
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 5:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File: 851378-2, flash-flv
    - Civil defense August 6, 1961, 851378-3
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 5:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File: 851378-3, flash-flv
    - Suggestions for getting the Senate into the twentieth century undated, 851378-6
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 5:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File: 851378-6, flash-flv
    - Aid to Latin America (Eisenhower administration) undated, 851378-7
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, neg, optical, 5:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File: 851378-7, flash-flv
    - With Hale Boggs May 5, 1963, [851378-8]
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 5:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File: 851378-8, flash-flv
    - With Esther Van Wagoner Tufty undated, 851378-9
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 5:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File: 851378-9, flash-flv
    - With Florence Hoff on televising Congress undated, 851378-10
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 5:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File: 851378-10, flash-flv
    - With Adlai Stevenson, ambassador to the United Nations undated, 851378-11
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, neg, optical, 5:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File: 851378-11, flash-flv
    - Trade bill (incomplete) undated, 851378-12
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 5:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File: 851378-12, flash-flv
    - State of the economy, letters from constituents on subject undated, 851378-13
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 5:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File: 851378-13, flash-flv
    - Time-Life interview on tax bill February 1962, 851378-14]
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, neg, optical, 5:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File: 851378-14, flash-flv
    - With Ralph Bellamy on the effects of the tax reform bill 1963 on actors, 1963, 851378-16
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 5:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File: 851378-16, flash-flv
    - With Edward R. Murrow on U.S. Information Agency March 1962, 851378-17
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 4:50
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File: 851378-17, flash-flv
    - With W. Averill Harriman April 24, 1962, 851378-18
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 5:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File: 851378-18, flash-flv
    - With Rand Dixon, Federal Trade Commission 0603, 851378-19.1
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 4:30
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File: 851378-19.1, flash-flv
    - With Rand Dixon, Federal Trade Commission 0603, 851378-19.2
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File: 851378-19.2, flash-flv
    - Possible tax reduction January 20, 1963, 851378-20
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 5:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File: 851378-20, flash-flv
    - How the tax cut will help Michigan July 28, 1963, 851378-22
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 5:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File: 851378-22, flash-flv
    - Latin American aid (20 nations) April 30, 1961, 851378-23
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 5:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File: 851378-23, flash-flv
    - Foreign aid, with administrative assistant Ann Penning July 16, 1961, 851378-24
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 5:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File: 851378-24, flash-flv
    - Housing October 25, 1961, 851378-25
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 5:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File: 851378-25, flash-flv
    - With Dr. Ralph Smith on FDA announcement on sale of antibiotics August 25, 1963, 851378-26
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 5:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File: 851378-26, flash-flv
    - International coffee agreement November 3, 1963, 851378-27
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 4:35
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File: 851378-27, flash-flv
    - Threats of nuclear war, especially to Flint and Detroit undated, 851378-28
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 5:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File: 851378-28, flash-flv
    - Introduction to WWJ's "Rails and roads" undated, 851378-29
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, neg, optical, 5:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File: 851378-29, flash-flv
    - Medicare bill (King-Anderson bill) undated, 851378-30
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, neg, optical, 5:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File: 851378-30, flash-flv
    - Fear of war; fear of unemployment; reciprocal trade with foreign nations undated, 851378-31
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, neg, optical, 5:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File: 851378-31, flash-flv
    - Congressional pay raises; jet runways at Selfridge Air Base undated, 851378-33
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, neg, optical, 5:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File: 851378-33, flash-flv
    - High cost of living; unemployment benefits; railroads; letters from youngsters undated, 851378-34
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, neg, optical, 5:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File: 851378-34, flash-flv
    - Presidential program for the mentally retarded undated, 851378-35
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, pos, optical, 5:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File: 851378-35, flash-flv
    - Medical care for the elderly and social security; excise taxes; Fiscal Policy Subcommittee of the Joint Economic Committee undated, 851378-36
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, neg, optical, 5:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File: 851378-36, flash-flv
    - Television bill (to televise congressional hearings, committees, and floor debate) undated, 851378-37
      - Original:, 16mm film, b/w, neg, optical, 5:00
      - Use Copy:, DVD (Box 2)
      - Streaming File: 851378-37, flash-flv
- Scrapbooks
  - 1961-1963 (Volume 1)
    (1)
  - 1970-1971 (Volume 2)
    (2)
  - 1971-1973 (Volume 3)
    (3)
  - 1973-1974 (Volume 4)
    (4)
  - August-December 1974 (Volume 5)
    (5)
  - 1974-1975 (Volume 6)
    (6)
  - 1975-1976 (Volume 7)
    (7)
  - Citations, awards, resolutions (Box 60)
Related Material
The Griffiths collection is unlike other congressional collections within the library in that certain kinds of materials were not received by the library and presumably were retained by the congresswoman. These include staff files, political or campaign files, speeches, and press files. Although Griffiths and her staff created a series of scrapbooks detailing her activities in Congress and for the two years following (1961-1963 and 1970-1976), her collection does not include a run of newsletters or press releases. According to Griffiths' biographer, Emily George, the congresswoman has retained "family memorabilia and political mementos," files of speeches, scrapbooks, newsletters, and her voting record in the Congress.